hi there my name is alert Bowser I'm the
嗨，我的名字是警报鲍泽，我是
CTO of driver comes to them and I'm
司机的首席技术官来找我
founder of axon framework and I'm here
轴突框架的创始人，我在这里
together with Josh hi everybody I'm Josh
和Josh在一起，大家好，我是Josh
long I'm a spring developer advocate at
很长一段时间，我是Spring开发人员的拥护者
pivotal and a pivotal we've been doing
我们一直在做的关键和关键
our level-headed best to help customers
我们头脑冷静的最佳服务客户
and community members and organizations
以及社区成员和组织
move to micro services they're looking
转向他们正在寻找的微服务
for ways to go faster and to reduce the
寻求更快的方法并减少
size of the batch of work that they have
他们拥有的工作量
to move through the value chain all the
在整个价值链中移动
way into production and we've seen a lot
投入生产，我们已经看到了很多
of organizations make this move and
的组织采取了这一举措，
they're using spring Buettner using
他们正在使用Spring Buettner使用
spring cloud to build these sort of
春天云来建立这种
distributed systems and one thing that
分布式系统和一件事
seems to come up a lot is how do we
似乎很多是我们如何
build you know distribute systems that
建立您知道的分发系统
have entanglements or have to understand
有纠结或必须了解
state in other node how do we get
在其他节点陈述我们如何得到
different nodes to agree upon state or
不同的节点同意状态或
to converge upon the correct state and
收敛到正确的状态
the one common pattern that seems to
一种似乎常见的模式
come up a lot is CQRS
很多是CQRS
so today we're very lucky to have a lot
所以今天我们很幸运
here join us in and introduce seekers
在这里加入我们并介绍寻找者
with the action framework which is a
行动框架
very very nice thing to use with spring
与弹簧配合使用非常非常好
but-- so like can you tell us what CQRS
但是-就像您能告诉我们什么CQRS
is so secure s means command and query
是非常安全的s表示命令和查询
responsibility segregation right it it
责任分工吧
basically means splitting components
基本上意味着拆分组件
into either something that handles
变成可以处理的东西
commands which are the intent to change
旨在更改的命令
something in in your system to change
系统中的某些东西需要更改
the application state versus the the
应用程序状态与
queries on the other side which give you
另一面的查询给你
insight in the current state of
对当前状态的洞察
applications and you already mentioned
应用程序，您已经提到
that different components need to agree
不同的组成部分需要同意
on a common common state and that's very
在一个共同的共同状态上，这是非常
often the case when you have a lot of
通常，当您有很多
different views on the same essentially
本质上不同的观点
the same data right there's a lot of
相同的数据有很多
different ways to look at information
查看信息的不同方法
contained in a system and different
包含在系统中并且与众不同
people have different requirements for
人们有不同的要求
those and that's exactly what's what cqs
那些，那恰恰是什么？
will will help you do it will help you
将帮助您做到这一点将帮助您
focus on the data that you need for for
专注于您需要的数据
each one of those those audiences on
这些观众中的每一个
these users of your of your data
您数据的这些用户
and you can do so in a distributed
你可以在分布式
system why is this architecture better
系统为什么这种架构更好
for distribution what do we get by
为了分配我们得到什么
building our applications in the secure
安全地构建我们的应用程序
way you know if we want to move to
您知道我们是否要移至的方式
distribute system for something out
分发系统的东西
something that is very common with the
这是很常见的
sucrose based system and it's not
基于蔗糖的系统，不是
essentially cqs itself does it says
本质上，CQ本身会说
nothing about distributed systems but
与分布式系统无关，但
it's very commonly used together with an
它非常常与
event-driven architecture and that's
事件驱动的架构，那就是
really where what the real power of of
真正在哪里
seacrest comes in as well and is you you
海冠也进来了，你是你吗
have these explicit messages that you
有这些明确的消息，你
can use so you have the intent to change
可以使用，因此您有改变的意图
something if you express that intent in
如果你表达了这种意图
a message then you can you can achieve
一条消息，然后你就可以实现
location transparency so you can achieve
位置透明，因此您可以实现
that one component the component sending
该组件发送的那个组件
the command doesn't know or need to know
该命令不知道或需要知道
where the component receiving and
组件接收和
processing that commands actually live
处理实际运行的命令
so that helps you build an application
这样可以帮助您构建应用程序
that you can distribute later even
以后甚至可以分发
whenever you need to and the same for
每当你需要和相同的
when you when you change something in a
当你当你改变一个东西
in a system you can invent events and
在系统中，您可以发明事件并
these events can then be handled in
然后可以处理这些事件
different components that updates
更新的不同组件
specific models for specific target
针对特定目标的特定模型
audiences with the data that these
受众与这些数据
audiences require so you can use these
听众要求，所以您可以使用这些
messages and optimize every component
消息并优化每个组件
separately which is a very nice
分开，这是一个非常好的
combination of features that you you can
可以组合的功能
use for for building distributed systems
用于构建分布式系统
oh very cool well okay I got my if
哦，很酷，好吧，我知道了
piqued my curiosity could you show us
激起我的好奇心，你能告诉我们吗
how to build a simple application
如何建立一个简单的应用程序
suppose I had a simple microserver set
假设我有一个简单的微型服务器
that had some state you know can we
有一些状态，你知道我们可以
build a simple example and see what it
建立一个简单的例子，看看它是什么
looks like - yeah build a mini play that
看起来像-是的，制作一部迷你剧
state service we want to build something
国家服务，我们想建立一些东西
quickly right so the best way to do that
快速正确，所以做到这一点的最佳方法
is go to startup spring the i/o and use
是在 spring boot I / O并使用
something that you're probably very
你可能非常
familiar with the spring initializer so
熟悉spring初始值设定项
we're going to start a little spring
我们将开始一个春天
boot application
启动应用
and I've been thinking about an
我一直在想
application where we can complain about
我们可以抱怨的应用程序
companies right so we're going to build
对的公司，所以我们要建立
a complaint application did a lot of
投诉申请做了很多
your web application I like to complain
您喜欢的Web应用程序
every now and then yeah it's it keeps me
每隔一段时间，是的，它让我
it keeps me motivated it's cathartic and
它让我充满动力，这是导泻和
so we put web and JPA hsqldb let's throw
所以我们将web和JPA hsqldb放到
in some mqp for for a bit later because
在稍后的一些MQP中，因为
we want to be doing some interesting
我们想做一些有趣的事情
stuff and don't think I'm missing
东西，不要以为我失踪了
anything right here that's alright so
这里的任何东西都很好
let's get started and let's unzip that
让我们开始吧，让我们解压缩
file and then start our project alright
文件，然后开始我们的项目
so here we are everything so this is
所以这里就是一切，这就是
just plain spring boots right it gets
只是普通的 spring boot 就可以了
you started in a few few seconds
你在几秒钟内开始
actually unfortunately we have to
不幸的是，我们不得不
manually add in the axon spring boot
手动添加轴突 spring boot
starter and currently we're going to use
入门，目前我们将使用
the release candidate one of maximum
释放候选最大
three so axonal three is almost it's
三个轴突，三个几乎是
almost done we're putting a lot of work
差不多完成了，我们要做很多工作
in and getting it out there but axonal
进去拿出来，但轴突
three has these spring boot starters
三个有这些弹簧启动器
that really kickstart your your
真正启动您的
application all right so that's all we
申请就可以了，仅此而已
need to do and then we go to our
需要做的，然后我们去我们的
application and this is our spring boot
应用程序，这是我们的 spring boot
application right our configuration so
应用正确的配置
let's build let's start off with
让我们开始吧
building a little API so a little league
建立一个小API从而建立一个小联盟
the rest
其余的部分
could you make define a little bit
你能定义一点吗
bigger
大
18 yep perfect
18完美
do we start over no looks good swim to
我们从头开始好好游泳吗
make sure we're all on the same page
确保我们都在同一页面上
I changed my final time very cool all
我改变了我的最后时间很酷
right
对
so we created this rest controller and
所以我们创建了这个rest控制器，
let's make get a method it's a public
让我们得到一个公开的方法
class static class and we call it a
类静态类，我们称之为
geyser to manipulate complaints exactly
间歇泉精确地处理投诉
so let's start with a little get nothing
因此，让我们从一点一无所获开始
so we have this HTTP GET request that we
所以我们有这个HTTP GET请求，
want to map to and always use void I let
想映射到并始终使用void我让
IDs do the typing they do a lot faster
ID的键入速度更快
than me so let's do a final method so we
比我好，让我们做一个最后的方法，所以我们
want to find all the complaints that we
想找到我们所有的抱怨
we have and to get that we need a
我们拥有并获得我们需要的
repository so we can create a complaint
仓库，以便我们可以投诉
and this is where the first little cqs
这是第一个小CQ
thing comes in and we create a complaint
事情来了，我们提出了投诉
query object repository want to be very
查询对象存储库要非常
explicit about the type of object that
明确说明对象的类型
we are using so we are serving out
我们正在使用，所以我们正在服务
information which is a query so we want
信息，这是一个查询，所以我们想要
to be explicit about that and we create
明确地说，我们创建
an interface which extends gapa
扩展差距的接口
repository we will be serving out
我们将提供的存储库
complaint query complaint query objects
投诉查询投诉查询对象
which are identified by a string
用字符串标识
and make that a repository now this
并建立一个仓库
object doesn't exist either so we create
对象也不存在，所以我们创建
that this is an API entity and we have
这是一个API实体，我们拥有
at id private string have a private
在id private字符串处有一个private
string script and a private string
字符串脚本和私有字符串
company that we want to complain about
我们要投诉的公司
this I like to avoid series create a no
我喜欢避免系列创建一个
our constructor and all our constructor
我们的构造函数以及我们所有的构造函数
just for later on all right so now we
只是为了以后，所以现在我们
have our repository we can make this
有我们的仓库，我们可以做到这一点
final and we add a post constructor
最后，我们添加一个后构造器
parameter Springvale yeah that will use
参数Springvale是的，将使用
the new support in Spring Framework 4.3
Spring Framework 4.3中的新支持
to automatically inject unambiguous
自动注入明确
resolvable collaborating objects into
可解析的协作对象
constructors even without auto wire
即使没有自动接线的构造函数
right correct so that just makes it
正确正确，这样就可以做到
simpler and less error-prone so let's
更简单，更不易出错，所以让我们
make their mapping so we have our
做他们的映射，所以我们有我们的
complaints query object from linked
链接的投诉查询对象
query object and we want to find a
查询对象，我们想找到一个
specific one so we can use a path
具体的一个，所以我们可以使用一条路径
variable string ID and we have to
可变字符串ID，我们必须
mention that in the request mapping and
在请求映射中提到
say ID so when if you're not if you're
说出身分证，这样就可以
not used to Spring Framework 4.3 then
然后不习惯于Spring Framework 4.3
you'll you'll not recognize these and
你会不会意识到这些，
get mappings and that post mapping
获取映射，然后发布映射
Caesar annotations that are shortcuts
凯撒注解是捷径
for at request mapping plus a specific
用于请求映射以及特定的
method introduced in for that three
这三个方法介绍
another nice feature
另一个不错的功能
yeah it makes it really clean right I
是的，它真的很干净我
like this a lot and of course we have
很喜欢这样，我们当然有
post mappings as well and this is where
以及发布映射，这是
more of the the actual use of seeker s
搜寻者的更多实际用途
becomes visible let's make it void for
变得可见，让我们对其无效
now
现在
and let the school we're going to create
让我们要创建的学校
something here right exactly we're going
这里的东西恰好我们要去
to do well to file a complaint and where
做好投诉的地方
this is a real server so we have a
这是一台真正的服务器，所以我们有一个
request body and let's just create a map
请求正文，让我们创建一个地图
of string to string and of course you
字符串到字符串，当然你
can create these these objects that
可以创建这些对象
contain all the data for you but this is
包含所有数据给您，但这是
just a quick and dirty way to to get our
只是一种快速而肮脏的方式来获得我们的
request on so don't we have something
要求，所以我们没有东西
now that's a P that'll be a map that
现在是一个P，它将成为一个映射
you're going to get from a JSON
您将从JSON获取
structure right that's right the JSON
正确的JSON结构
structure is translated to a map of keys
结构被翻译成键图
and values essentially so what we need
和价值观，因此我们需要
now is when somebody files a complaint
现在是有人提出投诉的时候
we want the system to do something for
我们希望系统为
us right so we're not asking for
我们是正确的，所以我们不要求
information we're telling it to do
我们告诉它要做的信息
something so this is where we pass in a
东西，所以这是我们传递的地方
command and in axon you have the command
命令，并在轴突中有命令
gateway to and to send commands and
网关并发送命令和
because we have included the spring good
因为我们包括了春天的美好
starter module we have all of the axon
入门模块，我们拥有所有的轴突
infrastructure at our disposal which is
我们可以使用的基础设施是
the command bus but also the event buses
命令总线，还有事件总线
and then some some more things that
然后还有一些其他的事情
we'll see a bit later on and the command
我们稍后会看到和命令
gateway is a very convenient API for for
网关是一个非常方便的API
sending commands so what we can do now
发送命令，以便我们现在可以做什么
is we can say send and we can just pass
我们可以说发送，我们可以通过
in an object that we want to send as a
在我们要作为对象发送的对象中
command so we want to send a file
命令，所以我们要发送文件
complaint command and we want to pass in
投诉命令，我们要传递
some information so request get and this
一些信息，所以要求得到和这个
is basically querying or getting data
基本上是查询或获取数据
from the our JSON structure let's say we
从我们的JSON结构中，我们说
have a company
有公司
and we do request get description and we
我们确实要求获得描述，我们
want to return what that method sends
想返回该方法发送的内容
back now this doesn't compile yet so
现在还没有编译，所以
it's not complaining about the void so
它不是在抱怨空隙，所以
we need to create this command object
我们需要创建这个命令对象
and we'll create it as an inner class
我们将其创建为内部类
this is there anything that we need I'm
这是我们需要的任何东西
sorry
抱歉
is there an ID or anything that we need
是否有ID或我们需要的任何东西
yes actually
是的，实际上
it is it is actually good practice to
这实际上是一个好习惯
pass in the identifier of the complaint
传递投诉的标识符
you're going to create and that's that
您将要创建，就是这样
might sound a bit weird like why would
听起来可能有点奇怪，为什么
you create an identifier before you've
您必须先创建一个标识符
created something but especially in
创建了一些东西，但特别是
distributed system is very convenient to
分布式系统非常方便
have what's called client generated
有所谓的客户端生成
identifiers so actually we could have a
标识符，所以实际上我们可以有一个
local variable here of type string and
这里的本地变量的类型为string和
use something random and your IDs are
使用随机的东西，你的ID是
typically a good good value for that and
通常来说，这是一个很好的价值，并且
so in that case we'll have an ID here as
所以在这种情况下，我们在这里有一个ID
well and now you can see it's
好，现在您可以看到
complaining about the return value I can
抱怨我可以返回的值
make it return a completable future and
使它返回可完成的未来
actually know that this case it's going
实际上知道这种情况
to be a string and so what this does is
成为一个字符串，所以这样做是
the command is sent and if the command
发送命令，如果命令
is executed asynchronously or maybe even
异步执行，甚至
remotely or wherever spring will only
遥远的地方或只有春天
send the response to the HTTP POST when
将响应发送到HTTP POST
the command is actually executed so by
该命令实际上是这样执行的
the time the UI gets the response the
用户界面获得响应的时间
command is dealt with but the thread
命令已处理但线程
that analog works in actually it
该模拟实际上起作用
released earlier I just worked naturally
早些时候发布我只是自然地工作
with the async support in Spring
在Spring中支持异步
Framework 3.1 in later write the
在以后的Framework 3.1中编写
completable future the a think results
可完成的未来
etc callable exactly so that's that's
等等完全可以调用，那就是
why the axonal API has exactly the same
为什么轴突API具有完全相同的
features you just pass them to two
您只需将它们传递给两个功能
spring and spring deals with it the way
春天和春天以这种方式处理
you would expect it does and so this is
你会期望的，所以这是
actually it now we can just send a
实际上，现在我们可以发送一个
sender command right so we
发送方命令正确，所以我们
requesting and a command is sent but
请求并发送命令，但
this command goes nowhere there's no
这个命令无处可去
component doing anything with this
组件与此做任何事情
command so we need to create that as
命令，因此我们需要将其创建为
well and in CQRS commands are are
好，在CQRS命令是
executed against a different model than
针对与其他模型不同的模型执行
the queries right the queries are there
查询正确，查询在那里
to get information out and the command
获取信息和命令
has a commander hat dealt with a dealt
有一个指挥官的帽子处理了
with by a separate model often returned
通过一个经常返回的单独模型
fir two as aggregates
冷杉二作为骨料
it's a domain driven design concept and
这是领域驱动的设计理念，
it means it's it's a number of entities
这意味着它是许多实体
that are kept in a consistent state with
保持与
regard to data changes so there is
关于数据更改，所以有
already this data change aspect in in an
该数据已经在
aggregate so we just create a class and
聚合，所以我们只创建一个类，
we call it complaint because that's what
我们称之为投诉，因为那是
it represents so I'm putting the
它代表了，所以我把
aggregate annotation which is an axon
聚集注释是轴突
annotation and I need to defy at least
注释，我至少需要违抗
one field which is the identifier of
一个字段，它是
this aggregate so I need to have the add
这个聚合，所以我需要添加
aggregate identifier annotation on it
聚合标识符注释
and now I can't create a command Handler
现在我无法创建命令处理程序
and I can in this case we want to create
在这种情况下，我可以创建
a new complaint instance right so when
一个新的投诉实例，所以当
the file complaint command comes in we
文件投诉命令进入我们
want to create a new instance of a
想要创建一个新的实例
complaint and we pass in the parameter
投诉，我们传递参数
the commander's parameter so action
指挥官的参数
we'll know when that command is sent its
我们会知道该命令何时发送
it creates a new instance of a complaint
它创建了一个新的投诉实例
now normally you would change the state
现在通常你会改变状态
in this in this handler right where
在这个处理程序中，在哪里
you've got something coming in and
你有东西进来，
normally you would do this dot ID equals
通常，您将执行此点ID等于
etc and that's not allowed what is
等等，那是不允许的
actually allowed in in cqs but what we
实际上在CQ中允许，但是我们
want to do here is event sourcing so we
想在这里做活动采购，所以我们
don't want to store the state of the
不想存储状态
complaint as is but instead we'll want
抱怨原样，但我们想要
to store all the events that have
存储所有具有
occurred with a complaint in the past
过去曾发生过投诉
and if we want to know the current state
如果我们想知道当前状态
all we need to do is replay or that's
我们需要做的就是重播，否则
actually what accent does for you
口音实际上为您带来了什么
you just replay all the events of a
您只需重播一个
specific complaint that happened in the
在发生的特定投诉
past and you will know the current state
过去，您将了解当前状态
but to be able to do that we need to
但是要做到这一点，我们需要
separate the decision-making from the
将决策与
actual state change logic so in here we
实际状态改变逻辑，所以在这里我们
do some decision-making and we could say
做一些决策，我们可以说
let's bring out some nice assert methods
让我们提出一些不错的assert方法
you can say has links come upon thoughts
你可以说思想上有联系
get company right we need information if
得到公司权利，我们需要信息，如果
we don't know what company you're
我们不知道你是哪家公司
complaining about is essentially useless
抱怨本质上是没有用的
if that's okay
如果可以的话
then we can apply a new complaint filed
然后我们可以提出新的申诉
event I seen some information from the
事件我从中看到了一些信息
command into the event and a good
指挥比赛并取得好成绩
company make sure we get the order right
公司确保我们得到正确的订单
otherwise we mess up somewhere else and
不然我们搞砸了
the apply method is something that we
apply方法是我们
can statically import from axon
可以从轴突静态导入
framework and this will do two things it
框架，这将做两件事
will publish this event internally and
将在内部发布此活动，并且
then so internally in this aggregate it
然后在内部汇总
will apply the state changes that belong
将应用所属的状态更改
with that event and it will publish the
该事件，它将发布
event to any components outside of the
事件发生在
aggregate in the application and as
汇总在应用程序中并作为
we'll see later on even outside an
我们稍后会看到
application and so we are going to
应用程序，所以我们要
create a little class and company yeah
建立一个小班和公司
and then bind it to us and then create
然后将其绑定到我们，然后创建
some getters right so that aggregate
一些吸气剂正确，以便聚集
when it's created in response to a
创建它以响应一个
command write everything every single
命令每一个都写
time there's a command with that
那个时候有一个命令
particular command axon is going to
特定的命令轴突将
create a new aggregate and if you have
创建一个新的聚合，如果有
different complaint IDs or have
不同的投诉ID或具有
different complaint aggregates they only
不同的投诉仅汇总
live for as long as that command handler
生存时间与该命令处理程序一样长
is active is that true yeah that's true
是活跃的，是的，是的，是的
so actually the of court of course
所以实际上当然是法院的
conceptually they live for a lot longer
从概念上讲，它们的寿命更长
but the actual object that's created
但是实际创建的对象
will only live during the handling of a
只会在处理
command and then the events are
命令，然后事件是
persisted and the the agri the aggregate
持续存在，农业总量
instance is just forgotten about unless
实例只是被遗忘了，除非
you use casual report which you can do
您可以使用随便举报
and who is persisting the the events so
谁坚持了这些事件
axon does that for you in the in the
轴突在
background so the the axon spring boots
背景，所以轴突 spring boot
starter will recognize that you're using
入门者会认识到您正在使用
JPA
JPA
and it will configure a table in in your
它将在您的计算机中配置一个表
database for you that contains all the
您的数据库，其中包含所有
events and it stores the complaint ID as
事件，并将投诉ID存储为
part of the metadata of those events so
这些事件的元数据的一部分，所以
when you load a specific complaint it
当您提出特定投诉时
can very quickly find all the events
可以很快找到所有事件
that happened as part of that complaint
这是该投诉的一部分
that single complaint so then based on
那个单一的投诉，然后基于
those events it can then reconstruct the
这些事件然后可以重建
the state all right cool and
状态好酷，
reconstructing the whole date was done
重建整个日期已完成
for event sourcing handlers and so I
对于事件源处理人员，所以我
could replay in theory the whole history
可以在理论上重述整个历史
right I could just I don't have to have
对，我可以不必
if I wanted to get back the state itself
如果我想回到国家本身
by event sourcing I could just zero it
通过事件源我可以将其归零
out basically and start again replay the
基本上退出并重新播放
events and get new state again exactly
事件并准确地再次获得新状态
and that's actually what happens on an
这实际上是发生在
aggregate all the time but you can also
始终汇总，但您也可以
do that on your own your query models so
自行执行查询模型
if you you've created a nice model but
如果您创建了一个不错的模型，但是
discover that you you have a different a
发现您与众不同
different view or maybe the performance
不同的观点或表现
could be better and you decide to
可能会更好，你决定
instead of refactoring it you can just
而不是重构它，您可以
throw away the entire model
扔掉整个模型
and then rebuild it from the beginning
然后从头开始重建它
beginning of time actually so since you
时间的开始实际上是这样，因为你
first launched the the application
首先启动了应用程序
depending on how many events you produce
取决于您产生多少个事件
in your application of course that could
在您的应用程序中
could take it a long time but at least
可能要花很长时间，但至少
you had the choice to do that and in
您可以选择这样做
most applications that are built
大多数已构建的应用程序
nowadays as soon as a let's say a
现在，让我们说一个
manager wants to have a different report
经理想要一份不同的报告
for which you don't capture the data the
您不捕获数据的
best you can do is say well we're going
最好的办法就是说我们要走了
to build it now then we'll go we'll put
现在建造它，然后我们就去放
it in production in about a month and
它在大约一个月的生产中
then we need to record data for three
然后我们需要记录三个数据
months and then you'll have your first
几个月，然后你会第一次
report but now instead you could say
报告，但现在您可以说
well give me a few minutes to to reload
好，给我几分钟时间重新加载
the entire history the least you'll have
最少的整个历史记录
your reports based on the beginning of
您的报告基于
time at least of your applications time
至少花费您的申请时间
so in this event sourcing handler this
所以在这个事件中，采购经理
this one is invoked by either the apply
这是由apply调用的
method or when we are loading an
方法或当我们加载一个
existing complaint from from a database
来自数据库的现有投诉
which is what would happen if you have a
如果您有一个
command handler on a regular method
常规方法上的命令处理程序
saying that you want to update some some
说你想更新一些
state so in this case you could say the
状态，因此在这种情况下，您可以说
complaint was resolved and then you can
投诉已解决，那么您可以
probably put in a and Happiness great or
可能会放在和幸福伟大或
something that you you want to pass in
您想传递的东西
but let's stick to the file complaint
但我们坚持对文件的投诉
now so we have some some state to keep
现在，我们有一些状态要保持
which is the complaint ID and we get
这是投诉编号，我们得到
from the event so when we are loading an
从事件开始，所以当我们加载一个
existing complaint this method is called
现有投诉称这种方法
and the complaint ID is set to the
并且投诉ID设置为
identifier contained in that and that
那和那个中包含的标识符
event so as I said the earlier he wrote
就像我早先说的那样
the purpose based event to the rest of
基于目的的事件
the components right
正确的组件
you're rehydrating the state of this of
你正在补充水分的状态
this complaint in that event sourcing
在该事件中的投诉
handler basically that's correct yeah
经理基本上是正确的
yeah and as you add more command events
是的，当您添加更多命令事件时
through your aggregate you'll have more
通过您的合计，您将拥有更多
of these events sourcing handler method
这些事件源处理程序方法
but say in some cases you'll even have
但说在某些情况下，您甚至会拥有
apply methods that apply in events that
应用适用于事件的方法
the aggregate itself is not interested
聚合本身不感兴趣
in it's just saying something changed
只是说有些改变
but if that change doesn't influence any
但是如果这种改变不影响任何
other commands then there's no need to
其他命令，那么就不需要
keep state for it in your in your
保持状态在你的
complaint object but and this this event
投诉对象，但是这个事件
sourcing handler is a not a great place
采购经理不是一个好地方
to put business logic right you're
建立正确的业务逻辑
applying the past you're recording the
运用您正在录制的过去
past here right that's the you're making
过去这里就是你正在做的
the aggregate exactly that's very
聚合恰恰是非常
important to realize you never reject an
重要的是要意识到你永远不会拒绝
event right don't don't put any
活动权不要放任何
validation here just imagine we didn't
验证这里只是想像我们没有
put the has length of the of the of the
放入的的长度
company in here so we have some some
公司在这里，所以我们有一些
companies or at least we have some some
公司，或者至少我们有一些
data in our database after running this
运行此命令后数据库中的数据
application for a while that has no
一段时间没有申请
company data if we would put the
公司数据，如果我们将
validation in here we would not be able
在这里验证我们将无法
to load those complaints anymore they
减轻他们的抱怨
would be rejected so don't reject the
将被拒绝，所以不要拒绝
event handler just accept whatever
事件处理程序只接受任何内容
happened you probably want to take
碰巧你可能想带
corrective action is something happen
采取纠正措施
that you really do not want to do have
你真的不想拥有
happened but it still did happen so
发生了，但还是发生了
don't put any validation there just
不要在这里放任何验证
accept well they accept history right so
接受得好，他们接受历史，所以
what we have now is we we have some get
我们现在拥有的是我们有一些得到
mappings that return us data we have a
返回我们数据的映射，我们有一个
command gateway that allows us to send
允许我们发送的命令网关
the command which emits an event but
发出事件的命令，但
there's one one little block missing and
有一个一小块的失踪，
that is to synchronize these two models
就是要同步这两个模型
right we've created a query model we've
对，我们已经创建了查询模型
created a command model which is our
创建了一个命令模型
complaint and but now we need to update
投诉，但现在我们需要更新
the query model with that based on that
基于该查询模型
event actually and so what we need to do
实际发生的事情，所以我们需要做什么
is we
是我们
radial component which is a public class
径向分量是公共类
as you can see I'm writing everything in
如您所见，我正在用
the same spring good application class
相同的春季良好应用类别
in there in a larger scale project you
在一个更大的项目中
probably wouldn't want to do that but
可能不想这样做，但是
for the for being quick we can do it
为了快，我们可以做到
this way and we do this we call this be
这样，我们做到这一点，我们称之为
compliant query object up and this one
符合条件的查询对象
will have an event handler in it and it
将有一个事件处理程序，它
listens to the complaint filed event so
听取投诉事件，以便
as you can see the parameter the of the
如您所见，
of the method defines the event where
方法的定义事件在哪里
we're interested in there's a few extra
我们感兴趣的是还有一些额外的
parameters you can pass in to get for
您可以传入以获得的参数
example metadata and values out of the
示例元数据和值
event or maybe even the timestamp of the
事件或什至是时间戳
event etc but in this case that's that's
事件等，但在这种情况下，那就是
not too important and of course we need
不太重要，当然我们需要
our little repository in here and object
我们这里的小仓库和对象
repository which we can then just out of
我们可以从中取出存储库
wire in there and we can save a new
连接到那里，我们可以保存一个新的
complaint query object based on the
基于的投诉查询对象
information we get from the event
我们从活动中获得的信息
like so and that's it awesome so that
就像这样，太棒了
was last missing piece that we should be
是我们最后应该丢失的一块
able to run this application and there's
能够运行该应用程序，并且
always is one little thing that you
永远是你的一件事
forget but if we did spring will tell us
忘记了，但是如果我们做了春天会告诉我们
no all right so we can go back to turn a
没有，所以我们可以回过头来
little console and we are going to send
小控制台，我们要发送
a post request and we want to pass in a
发布请求，我们想传递一个
header to tell the application that we
标头，告诉应用程序我们
have been sending Jason some data with
已经向Jason发送了一些数据，
it and this is a little JSON document
它，这是一个小的JSON文档
company is so what we're going to
公司就是我们要做的
complain about let's complain about
抱怨让我们抱怨
Apple and then description now I'm on a
苹果，然后描述我现在在
Windows machine complaining about Apple
Windows机器抱怨苹果
but imagine my Escape key is missing and
但是想像一下我的Escape键丢失了，
that's why I'm using my Windows machine
这就是为什么我使用Windows计算机
again because I didn't have an escape
再次因为我没有逃脱
key please send one there you go
钥匙请寄一个去
and we want to send that to localhost
我们想将其发送到本地主机
there we go but this is the UUID that we
我们去了，但这是我们的UUID
are sending and be careful in this
正在发送，请注意这一点
rendering that the two three I guess
渲染我猜这两个三
five as well is the speed and the rest
速度也是五个，其余的
of it is the response so don't make the
这是回应，所以不要
mistake of copying everything and then
复制所有内容，然后复制的错误
not finding that identifier and in your
找不到该标识符，并且在您的
in your database and so actually now we
在您的数据库中，所以实际上现在我们
could go to localhost 8080 and this is
可以去本地主机8080，这是
our final method right so we get that
我们最后的方法正确，所以我们得到了
complaint ID and Wow then we see the
投诉ID和哇，那么我们会看到
company and the description and we can
公司和说明，我们可以
even if we take that identifier that's
即使我们采用的标识符是
the other mapping we've created and we
我们创建的另一个映射，我们
get one the distance you see the square
距离您看到的正方形一倍
brackets aren't there right now it's
括号现在不存在
sending me one so let's put in another
寄给我一个，让我们放另一个
complaint just to make it slightly more
抱怨只是为了使它稍微多一点
interesting Microsoft's well what are we
有趣的微软很好，我们是什么
complaining about bash doesn't always
抱怨bash并不总是
work nicely there we go okay I put a
那里工作很好，我们可以，我放了一个
little quote that it didn't close here
小报价，它没有在这里关闭
see it's windows bash does not there we
看到它是Windows bash不存在，我们
go that was exactly our complaint ah and
去那正是我们的抱怨啊和
there you go now you've got two of them
你去那里，你现在有两个
here's the other complaint that is
这是另一个抱怨
that's alright one suffocation that's a
没错，那是一个令人窒息的
single node though so is there a way for
单节点，但是有没有办法
me to take what would phone to create a
我采取什么将电话创建一个
read-only view if I want to maybe
只读视图，如果我想
capture statistics is there some way I
捕获统计数据有某种方式
could um I don't want to do all that in
嗯，我不想做所有的事情
here right I want to keep that knowledge
在这里，我想保留这些知识
elsewhere and optimize for that
在其他地方进行优化
particular kind of storage how would I
一种特殊的存储方式
do you think so there's so there's two
你认为有两个吗
forces in play now so there's the
部队现在在比赛，所以有
securest that says you know I've got
最安全的说你知道我有
this different view of data so you want
您需要这种不同的数据视图
to see some statistics so let's say then
看一些统计数据，所以让我们说
the number of complaints of a specific
特定投诉的数量
company but that's so seekers basically
公司，但基本上就是这样
says well create a different model for
说好创建一个不同的模型
that and then micro-services says well
然后微服务说的很好
if you do something different build
如果您执行其他操作
another application for it right don't
另一个合适的应用程序不要
don't put all those features in a in a
不要将所有这些功能放在一个
new monolith actually and so what we can
实际上是新的整体，所以我们可以
do is we can push those changes to two
我们可以将这些更改推到两个
AMQP so let's publish our events out of
AMQP，所以让我们发布事件
this application because right now our
这个应用程序，因为现在我们
event bus is just contained within this
事件总线仅包含在其中
node right so we want to expose that so
节点正确，所以我们想公开它
we can do that by saying an acts on the
我们可以这样说：
AMQP dot exchange equals complaints
AMQP点交换等于投诉
events like that and so that's one thing
这样的事件，那是一回事
we need to do and the other one is make
我们需要做的，另一个是做
sure that acts on
确保行动
mqp is on the classpath there we go
mqp在我们去的classpath上
release candidate one as well so now
现在也释放候选人
axel mqp module is on the class path and
axel mqp模块位于类路径上，并且
it provides action with capabilities of
它提供具有以下功能的动作
sending data to two AMQP and and this
发送数据到两个AMQP
tells us the exchange that we want to
告诉我们我们想要的交流
forward these events to is is the
将这些事件转发给的是
complaint events exchanged and we need
投诉事件已交换，我们需要
to define those exchanges so so in
定义这些交流，所以在
rabbim queue you have a random queue the
rabbim队列中有一个随机队列
broker it has it's based on a open
它基于开放的经纪人
source an open protocol called AMQP AMQP
源一个称为AMQP的开放协议AMQP
describes the structure the
描述结构
infrastructure in a a message queue and
消息队列中的基础架构和
in AMQP you have a slight you know sort
在AMQP中，您有轻微的了解
of twist on the classic arrangement in
在经典的安排上的扭曲
message gives if you're used to for
消息告诉您是否习惯
example JMS you'll be used to a
示例JMS，您将习惯于
destination to which both producers and
生产者和
consumers to connect in RabbitMQ and QP
消费者连接RabbitMQ和QP
in general there's a little bit of extra
通常有一些额外的
indirection producers send messages to
间接生产者将消息发送到
exchanges and then exchanges route those
交流，然后交流路线
messages to queues to which a consumer
消息发送给消费者使用的队列
will then listen so what you're defining
然后会听，所以您正在定义
now are the the the moving parts here
现在是这里的运动部分
the exchange the queue and the binding
交换队列和绑定
between those two exactly so I want to
在这两个之间，所以我想
make sure I get the right name so I'm
确保我得到正确的名字，所以我
defining an exchange and then I'm going
定义一个交流，然后我要去
to define the queue
定义队列
just give them it would give them a name
只要给他们一个名字就可以了
queue builder dot let's create a durable
队列构建器点让我们创建一个持久的
queue so that's a queue that will
排队，这将是一个队列
survive and restart and we call that
生存并重新启动，我们称之为
complaint events as well why not keep it
投诉事件以及为什么不保留它
filled and now we need to tell our AMQP
填充，现在我们需要告诉我们的AMQP
our message brokers in this case rabbit
在这种情况下我们的消息经纪人
the the messages send to the complaint
邮件发送给投诉
events exchange need to be forwarded or
事件交换需要转发或
placed in the complaint event queue so
放置在投诉事件队列中，因此
we do that with a binding and we can say
我们通过绑定来做到这一点，我们可以说
returned from binding builder dot bind
从绑定构建器返回的点绑定
our queue to our exchange with and this
我们与之交流的队列
is which messages do you want to forward
您要转发哪些邮件
to which queue so you can pass in
到哪个队列，以便您可以传递
filters and and stuff like that we don't
过滤器和类似的东西，我们不会
want to do that we want to send
想做我们想发送的
everything so we will use star and then
一切，所以我们将使用星，然后
lastly because this there's only defined
最后，因为这只是定义
that we want to be able to use these
我们希望能够使用这些
exchanges it doesn't automatically
不会自动交换
create them and it's an mqp it's very
创建它们，这是一个mqp，非常
common to for an application to declare
申明的共同点
the queues that it requires and they are
它需要的队列，它们是
automatically created by their by the
由他们自动创建
broker so I can create it by the nice
经纪人，所以我可以创建它
thing about mqp
关于mqp
right it's one of the nice things about
对，这是关于它的一件好事
AMQP is that you can actually
AMQP是您实际上可以
programmatically in a standard way
以标准方式编程
create that create those moving parts
创造创造那些运动的部分
create the exchanges and the queues and
创建交易所和队列，以及
so on exactly so in a deployment you
在部署中完全一样
don't need to pass in I don't know
不需要通过我不知道
deployment documents to to the
部署文件到
Operations guys before deploying this
部署此之前的操作人员
application make sure these queues exist
应用程序确保这些队列存在
now you can define that you know
现在您可以定义自己知道
infrastructure as code actually so yeah
基础架构实际上就是代码，是的
so right now we have our admin and we
所以现在我们有我们的管理员，我们
declare our exchange and this is just
宣布我们的交流，这仅仅是
spring magic again right it's just you
春天的魔法再次对你
just put in the name key key exchange
只需输入名称密钥密钥交换
and then you declare q yeah and then you
然后您声明q是，然后您
declare the binding so this is normal
声明绑定，所以这很正常
spring configuration wiring that we're
我们的弹簧配置接线
we're doing here now we can restart her
我们现在在这里可以重新启动她
application I have my n QP management
我有我的QP管理人员
console open and we should see a Q not
控制台打开，我们应该看到一个Q
sure if it other ah there we go
确定是否其他啊，我们去
so we see our complaint events queue and
所以我们看到我们的投诉事件队列
it's completely empty obviously so let's
它显然是完全空的，让我们
put wish our or post our complaints
表示希望我们或发表我们的投诉
again this does not work nicely and now
再次，这不能很好地工作，现在
we have one and in a minute two messages
一分钟后有两条消息
waiting so our application is right now
等待，所以我们的应用程序是现在
pushing all the messages that all the
推送所有的消息
events that we're creating to to a queue
我们正在创建的事件排队
so now it's time to build the other side
所以现在该建立另一侧了
[Music]
[音乐]
to consumers now it alone so far you're
对消费者而言，到目前为止，您只是
showing so far you're showing us
显示到目前为止，您正在显示我们
rabbitmq are there other ways to
Rabbitmq还有其他方法可以
distribute this coming up is it possible
分发这个即将到来
to use thing else besides driving queue
除了驾驶队列以外还要使用其他东西
possibly yeah we're in the future really
可能是的，我们真的在未来
looking at Kafka for distributing events
看着卡夫卡分发事件
as well I mean it's a very common common
我的意思是，这是一个非常普遍的共同点
piece of technology to share events but
共享事件的一项技术，但
another may be one with threats as fine
另一个可能是受到威胁的人
agency is I'm sorry and that may be
代理机构，我很抱歉，可能是
another one will be as screen innovation
另一个将是屏幕创新
just using channels actually there's
只是使用频道而已
already a possibility to to forward
已经有转发的可能性
events to it to a channel as well and
到频道的事件以及
essentially with that you can use spring
基本上可以使用spring
cloud to forward it to anything that
云将其转发给任何
spring cloud supports which I guess is
我猜是春天云支持
going to be anything that's one way in
将成为任何一种方式
another interesting ways you can
另一种有趣的方式
actually use the event store as a
实际上将事件存储用作
message message source as well so you
消息源以及消息源
can have these components I mean the
可以有这些成分，我的意思是
events already stored in the event store
已存储在事件存储中的事件
anyway so you could have a component
无论如何，所以你可以有一个组件
track the events as they are stored in
跟踪事件存储在其中
the event store and then it will
事件存储，然后它将
remember where it left off by with a
记得用
token that it receives with every event
每个事件收到的令牌
so you can you can rebuild a career
这样你就可以重建职业
model completely by just throwing
只需投掷即可完全建模
everything away and deleting the tokens
一切都删除并删除令牌
and it will when when when it starts up
它会在何时启动
it will not have a token so we gain from
它没有令牌，所以我们从
the beginning and and reconstruct
开始和重建
everything powerful but now for our
一切强大，但现在对我们而言
statistics application we're going to
统计应用程序
keep it simple we're just going to
保持简单，我们只是要
create a little web application and
创建一个小的Web应用程序并
whether AMQP spring home could be source
AMQP Spring Home是否可以作为来源
right we call it demo complaint stats we
是的，我们称之为演示投诉统计
download the zip file we unzip demo
下载我们解压缩演示的zip文件
complaints stats
投诉统计
and we start this in IntelliJ so we have
我们从IntelliJ开始
a new window as a new application of
一个新的窗口作为
course again we need to add a dependency
当然，我们需要添加一个依赖项
acts on spring boot starter nope this
作用在弹簧启动启动器上不
one and we will add acts on AMQP as well
一个，我们还将在AMQP上添加行为
so let's go to our application now so
所以现在让我们进入应用程序
what we need to do is we need to fetch
我们需要做的是获取
those those events from from the channel
那些来自频道的事件
right yeah we do I think a bean and we
对，是的，我认为是豆子，我们
return a spring AMQP message source so
返回spring AMQP消息源，因此
this is an action component that allows
这是一个允许
our event handlers which we're going to
我们要处理的事件处理程序
create in a second to read from an AMQP
一秒钟创建即可从AMQP中读取
queue and then let's call it the
排队，然后我们称之为
complaint events as well and normally
以及正常情况下的投诉事件
you would have to build a simple message
你将不得不建立一个简单的消息
listener container forget it right and
侦听器容器将其忘记，然后
[Music]
[音乐]
let me just inject that so the
我来注入一下
serializer is something you get from the
序列化器是您从
the Springwood starter and so we do have
Springwood入门版，所以我们有
to create a little do fold in key
创建一点折叠
message converter which tells us how to
消息转换器，告诉我们如何
convert from a name could be message to
从名称转换可能是消息
to an axon message and but there's a
到轴突消息，但有一个
little trick that we can do because ring
我们可以做的小技巧，因为响
has much nicer ways to express reading
有更好的表达方式
for let's say I express the fact that
因为我说一个事实是
you want to read from a queue then
你想从队列中读取
defining a spring Messer
定义弹簧梅塞尔
simple message listener container plan
简单消息侦听器容器计划
though there's yet a trick and do it
虽然还有一个把戏
override the on-message method here just
仅在此处覆盖消息传递方法
leave it the way it is and just put in a
保持原样，然后放入
rabbit listener and we can say the queue
兔子监听器，我们可以说队列
that we want to listen to is what did we
我们想听的是我们做了什么
name it complaint if event queues
如果事件排队，则将其命名为投诉
complaint events right complaint events
投诉事件正确的投诉事件
so spring will invoke this method and
因此spring将调用此方法，
this method will then cause a an event
然后，此方法将导致一个事件
handler somewhere to be invoked and of
处理程序在某处被调用
course with that event and there is
当然有那个事件，有
something we need to define as well
我们也需要定义一些东西
let's create our little complaint
让我们制造一点抱怨
statistics a class it's not AB Union
统计不是AB Union的班级
we're going to create a little rest
我们要创造一点休息
controller we need an API on this we
控制器，我们需要一个API
have an event handler which is public
有一个公共的事件处理程序
doesn't even have to be and now of
甚至不必是现在
course we need the API of the other
当然我们需要另一个的API
application right we need some some way
申请权，我们需要一些方法
to to share the information and one way
共享信息和一种方式
to do that is by copying the class which
要做到这一点是通过复制类
is not something you would want to do in
不是你想做的事
let's say real life you would have a
假设现实生活中您会有
dependency on on a jar file or or even
依赖于jar文件或什至
better just only have the the formal API
更好的是只有正式的API
which is actually the the serialized
实际上是序列化的
form of that event and it has a
该事件的形式，它有一个
published document so you could have a
发布的文档，这样您就可以
serializer that transforms this into a
序列化器将其转换为
JSON document and sent that over AMQP
JSON文档，并通过AMQP发送
and then you only need to share how that
然后您只需要分享
date JSON document is structured but
日期JSON文档结构化但
since now both the producer and the
从现在开始，制作人和
consumer are acts on based applications
消费者是基于基础的应用程序
we can use the event classes
我们可以使用事件类
just make they're not hospice and the
只是让他们不是临终关怀和
nice thing is that they're not passing
好东西是他们没有通过
around the complaint aggregate or the
围绕投诉汇总或
Jaypee entity they're passing around
他们经过的Jaypee实体
events and that's it that's all you need
活动，仅此而已
to build re so they're just they have a
建立一个所以他们只是他们有一个
business meaning right those events are
这些事件是
not non-technical they are very
不是非技术性的，他们非常
functional objects and they should make
功能对象，它们应该使
very good sense to your product owner or
对您的产品所有者非常有帮助，或者
whoever whatever business people you
不管你是什么商人
build this application for
建立这个应用程式
so let's create a little a memory
所以让我们创建一些记忆
occurrence of a string which is a
出现的字符串是
company name - atomic long which is the
公司名称-原子长
number of complaints statistics that
统计的投诉数量
rights yes and we'll create a concurrent
是的，我们将创建一个并发
hash map now we can say statistics
哈希图，现在我们可以说统计
starts compute if absent so if there is
如果不存在则开始计算，如果存在
no and the first complaints for a
否，第一个投诉是
complaint for a company comes in we want
我们要投诉一家公司
to create a new atomic long and
创建一个新的原子长，
otherwise we want to get it and then we
否则我们想得到它，然后我们
want to increment that value and of
想要增加该值和
course we want to have a little request
当然我们要有一点要求
get nothing I don't think it mean and we
一无所获，我认为这并不意味着我们
want to say we have a map of string to
想说我们有一个字符串映射
atomic long
原子长
which is get statistics very nice word
这是统计数据非常好用的词
and we can just return a statistics so
我们可以返回统计信息
there's nothing nothing special we need
没有什么特别的，我们需要
to do here so this is just our this is
在这里做所以这就是我们的
our API ID it's a statistic and such
我们的API ID是一个统计数据，例如
that the stick oh it still has the
那根棍子哦，它仍然有
annoying tough to you to type there's
烦人的你很难打字
too many key Isis in different orders
不同顺序的关键Isis过多
that you need to put in so we're almost
您需要输入的内容，因此我们几乎
there right that we looks good we have
那里我们看起来不错，我们有
this message source that allows us to
此消息源使我们能够
read from a queue we have an event
从队列中读取，我们有一个事件
handler but acts on organizes these
经理，但行动组织这些
event handlers in in in so-called
所谓的事件处理程序
processors and processors by default
处理器和处理器默认情况下
they read from the event bus not from
他们从事件总线而不是从事件总线读取
some other source so we need to tell
其他来源，所以我们需要告诉
axon that this event handler needs to be
轴突此事件处理程序需要
put in a processor that actually reads
放入实际读取的处理器
from the queue and not from the event
从队列而不是从事件
bus itself and by default the name of
总线本身，默认情况下为
the processor is the name of the of the
处理器是的名称
package so in this case it would be calm
包装，所以在这种情况下会很平静
dot example which is not a very nice
点的例子不是很好
name so we can explicitly define now we
名称，所以我们现在可以显式定义
want this to be in let's say a.m. could
希望这个出现在我可以
be a mqp events something like that
成为mqp事件之类的东西
I know doesn't really matter that much
我知道没什么大不了的
and now in our application of properties
现在在我们的属性应用中
we can say axon dot let me double check
我们可以说轴突点让我仔细检查
for the main typos
对于主要的错别字
copy/paste there we go oops that we have
复制/粘贴在那里，我们会发现
accidental event ending dot processors
意外事件结束点处理器
and here we specify the name of the of
在这里我们指定的名称
the processor that we have which I have
我们拥有的处理器
already forgot and keep the events and
已经忘记并保留事件了，
we say the source of this is not the
我们说这不是
statistics queue or what name did we
统计信息队列或我们叫什么名字
give to it the complaint events no
给它投诉事件
that's not true that's not the source
那不是事实那不是来源
the source is this name is still
来源是这个名字仍然
complaint events so this is actually the
投诉事件，所以这实际上是
source that we want the nqp events
我们想要nqp事件的来源
processor to read from and that's it
要读取的处理器，仅此而已
that's the beanie it's just a big name
那是无檐小便帽，只是个大名声
of this this message source correct okay
此消息源正确无误
so they I mean isn't it this yep let's
所以我的意思是不是，是的，让我们
run it let's run and see so that there's
运行它，让我们运行并查看，以便有
a few messages waiting already so that
一些消息已经在等待，所以
should deplete our queue right away and
应该马上耗尽我们的队列
it's yeah of course ports already in use
是的，当然端口已经在使用中
of all the things that could go wrong
所有可能出错的事情
this is the one that goes wrong poor it
这是出问题的那可怜的吗
is 80 81 is enough to fix
是80 81足以修复
let's see if our queue is empty now yeah
让我们看看我们的队列是否现在是空的
it's gone
它消失了
so we go to localhost 8080 1 and see
所以我们去localhost 8080 1看看
what happens
怎么了
hey one complaint by Microsoft not bad
嘿，微软的投诉还不错
let's say now if we can do it in the end
现在说，如果我们最终能做到
let's do some Apple complaint and
让我们来一些苹果的投诉，
refresh this there you go here's your
刷新这个，你去这里是你的
Apple complaint and we can go here and
苹果投诉，我们可以去这里
see which complaint it actually was so
看看实际上是哪个投诉
that's our other service or is it Apple
那是我们的另一项服务，还是Apple
description my Escape key is missing and
说明我的转义键丢失，并且
of course this application was running
当然这个应用程序正在运行
before the other one in which we're
在我们所处的另一个之前
storing information in here that we did
我们在这里存储信息
not send to mqp yet and etc etc and
还没有发送到mqp等
that's another one did that's bar what
那是另一件事吗
blame not as nice as I would have
怪我不如我想的好
expected there you go yeah so that's
期待你去那里，是的
another Apple law you complained there
您在那里抱怨的另一项苹果法律
you go amid very cool look at that very
你会很酷地看着
easy way to reason about it if you
简单的方法来推理它，如果您
understand how to make to separate the
了解如何使
components logically in terms of
逻辑上的组件
commands and queries in the same note
同一注释中的命令和查询
that stands to be very easy when you do
当您这样做时，这很容易
that across distributed systems very
跨分布式系统
very convenient exactly and it doesn't
确实非常方便，而且没有
really matter where I mean I can copy my
真的很重要，我的意思是我可以复制我的
event handler and put it in the other
事件处理程序并将其放在另一个
application and we will it will just
应用程序，我们将它只是
work there as well right and that's
在那里正确地工作，那就是
that's what the location transparence
这就是位置的透明度
gives you and the the fact that you're
给你和事实，你是
distributing is just a matter of
分配只是一个问题
configuration the logic itself doesn't
配置逻辑本身不
change simply because applications are
更改仅仅是因为应用程序
distributed so now you can really focus
分散，所以您现在可以真正专注
start focusing on on getting the
开始专注于获得
business logic right first and then when
首先是业务逻辑，然后是什么时候
it's right and you can address the the
是的，您可以解决
pain points or the the parts that you do
痛点或您要做的部分
want to be scalable or you want to take
想要扩展或想要
out of there and then take them out as
从那里拿出来
as to see fit so you don't have to start
看起来合适，所以您不必开始
with a massive distributed system but
拥有庞大的分布式系统，但
you can have evolved into one and
你可以进化成一个
or as your application grows awesome
或者随着您的应用程序变得越来越强大
are there any takeaways any things that
有没有什么外卖的东西
people should understand when they
人们什么时候应该明白
anything else you should understand
你应该了解的其他任何事情
before they look at the stuff any text
在他们看东西之前，任何文字
you might read I recommend rather well
你可能会读我很好推荐
there's a very interesting article by
有一篇非常有趣的文章
actually by Microsoft it's called the
实际上由Microsoft称为
seeker s journey which is which is a
寻求者的旅程
good read and it gives you a good
好的阅读，它给你一个很好的
overview on a lot of these aspects that
这些方面的概述
are not essential CQRS but often
不是必不可少的CQRS，但通常
combined with it like event sourcing I
像事件采购一样与之结合
mean seeker s an event sourcing are two
平均搜寻者的事件来源是两个
completely different things secure s in
确保完全不同的事物
distributed systems and seeker s an
分布式系统和搜寻器
event-driven architecture they're all
事件驱动的架构
separate things but they combine
分开的东西，但它们结合在一起
together really nicely and that's what
在一起真的很好，就是这样
the the document also describes so it's
该文档还描述了
called seeker s journey and it really
叫做寻找者的旅程
described there's a good job in in
说在里面做得很好
describing all these little
描述所有这些小事
architectural components that you can
可以的建筑组件
put together to create a very nice
放在一起创造一个非常好的
distributed system that is actually
实际上是分布式系统
pretty easy to maintain as well
也很容易维护
and the the project right now is
现在的项目是
marching towards a 300g a are there what
朝着300克前进
it would aren't any features you'd like
它不是您想要的任何功能
to have or see rather in the sort of
以某种方式拥有或看到
future I mean and do want feedback do
未来，我的意思是，也想反馈
you want to people to try the bit oh
你想让人尝试一下哦
yeah please please try I mean its
是的，请尝试我的意思是
release candidate one there's actually
释放候选人实际上
already some companies in production
已经有一些公司投入生产
with it as it stands right now whether
现在的状态是否
you want to do that yourself is of
你想做自己的事
course really up to you but I would
当然取决于您，但我会
would ask you please give it a try and
会问你请尝试一下
since we are not GA yet we we welcome
由于我们不是GA，因此我们欢迎您
all feedback that that we can get to to
我们可以得到的所有反馈
make sure that the API is the most
确保API是最
pleasant to work with as possible and
尽可能愉快地工作
then yeah we can still make little
那是的，我们仍然可以赚一点钱
adjustments to to those API so this this
调整到那些API，所以这
would be the the time to do that you
是时候做你了
know you're allowed you nya you and I
知道你被允许你你我
have known each other for a better part
彼此相识更好
of I don't know better part of a decade
我不知道十年的大部分时间
now and one of the original places where
现在，原来的地方之一
we where we talked was in terms of an
我们所说的是
info Q article that I wrote about you
我写的有关您的信息Q文章
years ago many years ago about you know
多年前关于你知道
about 5 or 6 years ago I think yeah and
大约5或6年前，我认为是的，
that that journey watching accent as
那段旅程看着重音
it's going over the years you know and
这是你知道的几年
now we you know the code that we have to
现在我们知道了我们必须执行的代码
write to get a reasonable solution up
写信以获得合理的解决方案
and running it's just diminished to
而运行它只是减少
nothing right is really really really
没事真的是真的
well done I love the result it's been a
做得好，我喜欢这个结果，
quite a journey there as well think that
还有一段漫长的旅程，并认为
I mean that's most part of that is the
我的意思是，最重要的是
way spring brute works and I think that
春天暴力的工作方式，我认为
is I mean I was I was actually amazed
我是说我当时真的很惊讶
myself when I started implementing this
我自己，当我开始执行这个
you get to a point like oh is that it
你会达到这样的地步哦
but yeah the excellent one and acts on
但是是的，优秀的演员
to as well you needed a lot of
同样，您需要很多
boilerplate to just to get started right
入门指南
you needed the command bus in the event
您需要在事件中使用命令总线
bus and for every aggregate you needed
公交车和您需要的每个集合
all these components
所有这些组成部分
now you put an annotation on there
现在你在上面放一个注释
there's a spring that works really
有一个春天真的很有效
nicely with you just declare things and
和你一起很好地声明东西
then spring helps you and of course
那么春天可以帮助你，当然
there's a axle on spring boots starter
spring boot 启动器上有一个轴
in between but auto-configuration
在中间但自动配置
everything yeah it auto configures
是的，它会自动配置
everything that you want and still
您想要并且仍然想要的一切
allows you to modify every bit in piece
允许您修改每一部分
as you as you see fits right if the
如您所见，如果
defaults aren't your defaults then you
默认值不是您的默认值，然后您
can change them if you want that's that
可以更改它们，如果您想那样的话
makes it really powerful so I think axon
使其功能强大，所以我认为轴突
together with spring boots is definitely
搭配 spring boot 绝对是
something that yeah it gets you started
是的，它可以帮助您入门
quickly because of spring boots and I
很快因为我和 spring boot
always say axle isn't built to get you
总是说不是为了让你动起来
started quickly but it's built to keep
快速启动，但旨在保持
you going for a long time and I think
你走了很长时间，我想
that that combination works for works
该组合适用于作品
very well I do too thank you so much for
我很好，我也非常感谢你
showing me all this and for showing all
向我展示所有这些，并为我展示所有
of us what's happening with accent very
我们当中非常有口音的人
very cool and with that I think we
非常酷，我想我们
should turn to the questions and answers
应该转向问题和答案
don't you think yeah let's answer for
你不认为是的，让我们来回答
your questions so if you have them use
您的问题，如果您有他们使用
the chat to to ask your questions and
聊天以询问您的问题和
we'll we'll start answering them now
我们将开始回答他们
[Music]
[音乐]
all right well that was a very good very
好的，那是一个非常非常非常
good look at Exxon and how to build a
很好地了解埃克森美孚以及如何建立
you know speakers based systems with
你知道基于扬声器的系统
spring Putin accent thank you so much
春天普京口音非常感谢你
for ed alert now we've got a lot of
对于ed警报，我们现在有很多
questions here so I think we should um
这里的问题，所以我认为我们应该
see if we can tackle as many of them as
看看我们是否能解决尽可能多的问题
we can as quickly as possible
我们可以尽快
first of all why not use spring cloud
首先，为什么不使用Spring Cloud
stream uh and I love yeah go on yeah go
流呃，我爱是的，继续
ahead
先
oh yeah that was that's a that's a very
哦，是的，那是一个非常
good question and we we have some
好问题，我们有一些
support for spring cloud already which
对Spring Cloud的支持已经
is actually the the spring messaging
实际上是春天的消息
part so there are some adapters in an
因此，在其中有一些适配器
axon but we are looking into a better
轴突，但我们正在寻找更好的
integration with a spring cloud in
与弹簧云集成
general so yes dream would be would be
一般，是的，梦想将会是
one of them if we've also remove vision
其中之一，如果我们也移除了视力
yeah yeah I mean you can use spring
是的，我是说你可以用弹簧
cloud stream with this the messaging
云流与此消息传递
support and spring right good spring
支撑和弹簧好弹簧
cultivators - yeah the message channel
中耕者-是的，消息通道
for you so you can already use the the
为您服务，因此您已经可以使用
the acts on the spring messaging adapter
Spring消息传递适配器上的行为
for getting axon messages transformed
用于转换轴突消息
into bring messages and then send them
带来消息然后发送给他们
over spring channels where you could
在春天的渠道，你可以
have spring clouds stream then for them
然后有春天的云流为他们
to whatever they support yep but the
不管他们支持什么，但是
other thing we're also looking at is for
我们也在寻找的另一件事是
example spring spring cloud discovery
春季春季云发现示例
and there's I mean spring cloud is
我的意思是春天的云是
pretty pretty big and there's a lot of
相当大，而且有很多
interesting stuff going on there
有趣的东西在那里
but our focus right now is a bit more on
但是我们现在的重点是
on getting the api's right and as soon
在正确使用api上
as they're right getting that stuff in
因为他们说对了，
is it's just a matter of time and uh
这只是时间问题吗
sonic right let's see when will the
音速吧，让我们看看
excellent three Quick Start Guide be
优秀的三个快速入门指南
available on the X and website I'd
我可以在X和网站上找到
reckon right after the GA version of act
在GA版本的行为之后立即考虑
on ships that fair yeah maybe even even
在公平的船上，甚至甚至
before but yeah probably somewhere
以前但是可能在某个地方
around that that time
那个时候
currently we've got some some people
目前我们有一些人
looking at a different way to to get the
寻找另一种方式来获得
QuickStart guide up and running and some
快速入门指南，运行和一些
a bit more interactive than just oh
互动比不仅仅是哦
here's a web page and do what it says
这是一个网页，按照它说的做
and you'll have a little application
然后你会有一个小应用
going and so we hope to be able to get
去，所以我们希望能够得到
that in and otherwise it will just be a
在，否则它将只是一个
page telling you what to do
告诉你该怎么做的页面
plus I think just I think today's
再加上我认为今天
session was a very good QuickStart so
会议是一个很好的快速入门，所以
hopefully it'll survive exactly
希望它将完全生存
something that that's a little video
那是一个小视频
well we're going to it has been recorded
好，我们要去录制了
and it will be published some sometime
它将在某个时候出版
soon so then we'll act as a little Quick
很快，那么我们将作为一个快速
Start Guide right yeah absolutely
入门指南完全正确
is since the query object repository is
是因为查询对象存储库是
just a JTA repository what this
只是一个JTA存储库
integrate with spring data rest and
与spring数据架集成
programmatically generate the query API
以编程方式生成查询API
yeah you can you can use spring data
是的，你可以使用弹簧数据
rest to generate the the view model for
休息以生成视图模型
that the view service for that a that
该那个的视图服务
model the second part that question is
建模问题的第二部分
any thoughts on how to reduce the amount
关于如何减少用量的任何想法
of oil plate and accepting commands well
的油盘并很好地接受命令
okay so you wouldn't use okay the
好的，所以您不会使用好的
question here for you as a a thoughts on
在这里向您提出问题
how to reduce the amount of boilerplate
如何减少样板数量
in accepting command through the REST
通过REST接受命令
API yes yes absolutely we've been
API是是绝对我们已经
thinking about just exposing end points
考虑只是暴露终点
where you can can send commands however
您可以在其中发送命令的地方
in practice what we see is that you
在实践中，我们看到的是你
don't always want your your events one
并不总是希望您的事件之一
on us or your commands one on one as as
在我们或您的命令上一对一
API invocations and typically also
API调用，通常也
because you have these class names in
因为您在这些类名中
there and as soon as you you open up
在那里，一旦你打开
that way well there's some potential
这样一来，就有一定的潜力
leaks so security leaks in there I meant
泄漏，所以那里的安全漏洞
to say and so yes we are looking at some
说，所以是的，我们正在看一些
some way to make a very generic to get
使非常通用的某种方式
commands out or at least commands in
发出命令或至少发出命令
based on
基于
a REST API but yeah in practice we see
REST API，但实际上我们看到了
that there's you know there's there's
你知道那里有
not a real one-to-one mapping from the
不是真正的一对一映射
front end anyway
反正前端
are there any changes when you are using
使用时有什么变化吗
a different mq so in this case we use
不同的mq，因此在这种情况下，我们使用
the revenue mq I suppose we could use
我想我们可以使用的收入mq
the spring message channel thing which
春天消息频道的事
would then talk to anything that spring
然后会在那个春天跟任何人说话
innovation could talk to you right so
创新可以正确地与您交流
that would be yeah right so accident in
是的，所以在发生意外
itself only supports AMQP or spring
本身仅支持AMQP或spring
messaging right now and in MKP it only
即时通讯，仅在MKP中
uses spring AMQP so yeah those are the
使用春季AMQP，是的，这些是
options and probably well probably I
选项，也许我很可能
mean by supporting spring clouds stream
通过支持 Spring Cloud Stream 意味着
indirectly at the moment but it's
目前是间接的，但是
probably more directly in the near
可能更直接地在附近
future and we support everything that
未来，我们支持一切
spring supports right on any MC it may
弹簧可以在任何MC上支撑
seem data center
似乎数据中心
what about AWS integration and actually
AWS集成又如何呢？
the I want to rephrase a question what
我想改个问题
is it look like to use this in the cloud
看起来像在云中使用它
in different environments are there any
在不同的环境中有
you know in AWS it's gonna be different
您知道在AWS中会有所不同
from for example more opinionated
从例如更固执
platform like well for example plaid
像格子这样的平台
sangria Heroku in Google App Engine so
Google App Engine中的桑格利亚汽酒Heroku，因此
when you speak to that there's it
当你说话的时候
there's a few few things first of all is
首先有几件事是
just an app like any other application
就像其他应用程序一样
right the axon stuff is mostly within
对，轴突的东西大部分在
the JVM at least in our our example here
至少在我们的示例中，JVM
when we get out of the JVM we use MV in
当我们离开JVM时，我们在MV中使用
this case you could use but it's not
这种情况下您可以使用，但不是
available out of the box but you could
开箱即用，但您可以
use the simple queue service
使用简单的队列服务
bye-bye AWS to do that but for therefore
再见AWS做到这一点，但为此
the scalability part currently we only
目前，我们仅可扩展性部分
support J groups and you can get J
支持J组，您可以获得J
groups to work on AWS you just don't use
小组在不使用的AWS上工作
the for the discovery just use a gossip
对于发现只是使用八卦
server for example but it's not the most
例如服务器，但不是最
ideal and that's one of the things we're
理想，这是我们要做的事情之一
looking at
看着
we're looking at spring cloud discovery
我们正在寻找春季云发现
is to to support that and that will
是为了支持那个，那将
definitely boost the the ability to run
绝对提高了跑步能力
axon based applications at scale on on
基于轴突的应用规模不断扩大
cloud environments discovery final sorry
云环境发现最后对不起
yeah the discovery client abstraction in
是的，发现客户端抽象在
spring cloud exactly yeah
春天的云正好
uses everything when axon has is an
当轴突有一个
interface so it's relatively simple to
界面，因此相对来说比较简单
do to implement something very specific
做一些非常具体的事情
to two specific environments if you have
到两个特定的环境（如果有）
a different way to discover nodes or
发现节点的另一种方法或
have a different way on AWS for example
例如在AWS上有不同的方式
you could just use API is to find all
您可以使用API​​来查找所有
the nodes that you're running and then
您正在运行的节点，然后
discover which ones of those are actual
发现其中哪些是真实的
nodes etcetera etcetera so um let's see
节点等，等等，让我们来看看
how about rate okay let's see how option
怎么样率好吧，让我们看看如何选择
steps for action could you talk about
您可以谈谈采取行动的步骤
who's using it how they're using it
谁在使用它，他们如何使用它
cetera yeah well there's of course I can
是的，我当然可以
not do a lot of name dropping because x1
没有做太多的名字删除，因为x1
is quite often used in actually a
实际上经常用于
mission critical systems and companies
关键任务系统和公司
that are relatively secretive about them
对他们来说比较秘密
using it unfortunately but I can say
不幸地使用它，但是我可以说
there's some some very large banks using
有一些非常大的银行使用
it some of them are using it for for
他们中的一些人将其用于
payment processing which we've seen a
付款处理，我们已经看到了
stock trading based on on axon there's a
基于轴突的股票交易
lot of financial applications in in
大量的财务申请
general but also mostly they're they're
一般，但大多数情况下，他们是
transactional systems and and some of
交易系统和一些
them run at large scale there's one one
他们大规模运行，只有一个
customer I call the kazoo Moe I'm
客户我称我为kaazoo Moe
allowed to mention them they're an
允许提及他们，他们是
online casino and they they have really
网上赌场，他们真的有
strong auditing requirements by the
审核员提出了严格的审核要求
government obviously because they're a
政府显然是因为他们是
casino and today they use they store the
赌场，今天他们使用它们存储
entire history of the application since
自申请以来的全部历史
about five years now or six years
现在大约五年或六年
do they have billions of
他们有数十亿
in there it's actually my sequel
在那里实际上是我的续集
database that they have tweaks and
他们有调整的数据库
optimized to store that amount of data
优化以存储该数据量
so right now we don't know real numbers
所以现在我们不知道实数
because we it's an open source project
因为我们这是一个开源项目
and names keep keep on appearing every
和名字不断出现
now and then we suddenly see a name that
有时我们突然看到一个名字
publishes a job posting for example
例如发布职位发布
looking for somebody with excellent
寻找优秀的人
experience well you only do that if you
经验丰富，只有当你
have accent applications running I
有运行我的口音应用程序
suspect and but we expect there to be at
怀疑，但我们希望在
least a few thousand implementations in
至少有数千个实现
production right now right on what what
现在就生产什么
about Kafka
关于卡夫卡
instead of rabbitmq and I think you
而不是rabbitmq，我想你
spoke a little bit about this but can
谈了一点，但是可以
you speak to that some more yeah so a
你说的更多，是的
Kafka is currently well not supported
目前不支持Kafka
well not yet I mean there's no
好吧，我还没有
out-of-the-box
盒子外面
Kafka component four four four acts on
卡夫卡成分四四四作用
however it yeah it would definitely be a
但是，肯定是
really good implementation for an event
一个事件的很好实现
bus and it's it's on our roadmap we're
公交车，这就是我们的路线图
expected to we expect to be able to
期望我们期望能够
include it in three point one some
包括三点一
people argue that you could also use it
人们认为您也可以使用它
as an event store because basically you
作为事件存储，因为基本上
can set the the event lifetime to
可以将事件生存期设置为
indefinite and then Kafka will allow you
无限期，然后Kafka将允许您
to do replays from the beginning as well
也可以从头开始重播
I'm not 100% convinced that's a good
我不是100％相信这是件好事
thing to do because it Kafka is not
要做的事情，因为它不是卡夫卡
designed to do that it is able to do it
旨在做到这一点
but yeah if you store events for a long
但是，如果您将事件存储很长时间，
time and then it's you better have a
时间，然后你最好有一个
system that is designed to store those
用于存储这些信息的系统
events for a long time and preferably
事件持续了很长时间，最好
forever so that would be my advice but
永远，所以这将是我的建议，但是
definitely Kafka is a very good way to
绝对是卡夫卡是一个非常好的方法
get events from from one machine to many
从一台机器获取事件到多台
others very cool um who well when I went
其他人很酷，嗯，我去的时候很好
to enter this one one one comment was it
输入此一个一对一的评论是吗
that he didn't realize you could avoid
他没有意识到你可以避免
sticking at auto wire Donna
坚持在自动电线唐娜
on a constructor and now I want to point
在构造函数上，现在我要指出
out that that's new and Spring Framework
这是新的，Spring Framework
4.3 which is now in spring group 1.4
4.3现在是春季分组1.4
which is what we were using in this demo
这就是我们在本演示中使用的
so that would have worked for anything
这样对任何东西都有效
in the last oh I don't know a few months
最后一次，我不知道几个月
or this year basically since we had a
或今年基本上因为我们有一个
spring boot so our Spring payment for
spring boot ，所以我们的春季付款
that three so um who does the apply
那三个谁来申请
method in the constructor is a what does
构造函数中的方法是做什么的
the apply method in the constructor
构造函数中的apply方法
that's the question
这就是问题所在
it was it what does it do yeah that's so
是它是做什么的，是的
apply and the apply method does
应用，并且应用方法可以
essentially does two things first of all
本质上首先要做两件事
within the aggregate itself
在聚合本身内
so within our complaint it would find
因此在我们的投诉中，它会发现
all the handlers so the add event
所有的处理程序，所以添加事件
sourcing handlers in there and invoke
在那里找到处理程序并调用
them just right away right there's no
他们马上就没有
waiting involved and when they are
等待参与以及何时参与
invoked the the event is also stays for
调用该事件也将保留
publication with the event bus and when
与事件总线一起发布以及何时发布
the command execution completes there
命令执行在那里完成
there's a little unit of work around
周围有一小部分工作
that command execution that unit of work
该命令执行该工作单元
will start the commit process and the
将开始提交过程，并且
first step in that process is get the
该过程的第一步是获取
events out the labels to go and store
事件出标签去存储
the events in the event store depending
事件存储中的事件取决于
on the type of for example the mqp
在例如mqp的类型上
connection that you have if it's
您拥有的连接
transactional it will send the events
事务性的它将发送事件
right away as well but with an open
马上开放
connection and wait for the commits - it
连接并等待提交-它
will come in the next phase and there's
将会进入下一阶段，
a commit phase where all the commits are
一个提交阶段，其中所有提交都是
done and then there's a not-so commit so
完成，然后有一个不是这样的提交，所以
that's how everything is coordinated but
这就是一切协调的方式，但是
the apply method will internally apply
apply方法将在内部应用
it to invoke all the handlers and then
它调用所有处理程序，然后
stages for publications for the rest of
其余阶段的出版阶段
the world as a next step okay cool um
下一步就是好世界
the one question was seems like the
一个问题似乎是
questions aren't working but then of
问题不起作用，但是
course there's a question so huh you
当然有一个问题，所以你
know um can you show what the event
知道你能告诉我什么事吗
sourcing table looks like so we used H
采购表看起来像这样，所以我们使用了H
sequel or h2 in this right so do you
续集或H2在这个权利，你呢
have anything you can show us yeah I
有什么可以告诉我们的，是的，我
shut down the IDE so they're gone
关闭IDE，使它们消失
but I should be able to because I
但我应该能够因为我
switched off screen share should be able
关闭屏幕共享应该能够
to get screen share back on and let me
重新获得屏幕共享，让我
first start my sequel workbench because
首先启动我的续集工作台，因为
I'm pretty sure I have some of course I
我很确定我当然有
can talk about it but let's let's get it
可以谈论它，但让我们开始吧
up there so I should have a table in
在那里，所以我应该有一张桌子
here all right let me screen share let's
好吧，让我分享屏幕内容吧
see what happens
走着瞧吧
all right so you should be able to see
好的，所以您应该能够看到
this and and I can select these rows and
这个，我可以选择这些行
here you see a few if you're in banking
在这里，您会看到一些如果您在银行业务
sorry this is yeah this is my view of
抱歉，这是我的观点
banking I me just withdraw money let you
银行我我只取钱让你
see it there's a global indexed there's
看到那里有一个全球索引
an event identifier which is a unique
一个事件标识符，它是唯一的
message identifier and this is mainly
消息标识符，主要是
for our correlation purposes and then
为了我们的相关目的，然后
there's two blobs one for metadata and
有两个Blob，一个用于元数据，另一个用于
one for the payload and then within
一个用于有效载荷，然后在
those blobs you can see the actual or in
这些斑点，您可以看到实际或
this case is just the XML by default
这种情况下默认情况下只是XML
Exim uses extreme to serialize the event
Exim使用Extreme来序列化事件
so this is a serialized event and then
所以这是一个序列化的事件，然后
there is a description of what the
有关于什么的描述
payload is actually is and the reason
有效载荷实际上是原因
for that is axon will only deserialize
因为那是轴突只会反序列化
the event if there is a handler for it
该事件是否有处理程序
but uses ladydi serialization when it's
但是当它使用ladydi序列化时
it's very common that a an aggregate
聚合是很常见的
publishes events it's not interested in
发布不感兴趣的事件
itself because it doesn't affect any of
本身，因为它不影响任何
the state of the aggregate itself and in
聚合本身及其内部的状态
that case such an event is not be
这种情况不是
serialized when when loading an
加载时序列化
aggregate and then there's a timestamp
汇总，然后有一个时间戳
and then there's the aggregate
然后有合计
identifier and sequence number and those
标识符和序列号以及那些
are used to load all the events of a
用于加载所有事件
specific aggregate instance these are
具体的聚合实例是
not very sensible identifiers to use but
不是很明智的标识符，但是
this was for demo and then there's a
这是为演示，然后有一个
type which is the the type of aggregate
type是集合的类型
I doubt it's used anywhere in axon but
我怀疑它在轴突的任何地方都可以使用，但是
we've we've noticed that this is very
我们已经注意到这是非常
useful if you're debugging so we add the
如果您正在调试，则非常有用，因此我们添加了
type there as well in action - there's a
在行动中也要输入-有一个
type column as well and it's part of the
以及键入列，它是
unique identifier of the aggregates in
集合中的唯一标识符
axon 3 it's just it's not indexed at all
轴突3只是根本没有索引
it's just there for for us - well us and
对我们来说就在那里-好吧，我们
you for for debugging so that's it great
您进行调试，非常好
very cool that I think that should be
我认为应该很酷
very illuminating for requester um
对于请求者来说非常有启发性
that's D in it when can you speak about
那是D，什么时候可以谈论
when the GA will be done for a version
何时完成版本的GA
that Torito treated oh what's the one of
Torito对待的哦，那是什么之一
the plans ooh
计划哦
it's a dangerous question to answer but
回答这个问题很危险，但是
I'm going to give it a go anyway so
我还是去试试看
right now we are on release candidate
现在我们正在发布候选
one and we invite everybody to provide
一个，我们邀请大家提供
us with feedback and basically it
我们有反馈，基本上
depends on how much feedback we get we
取决于我们得到多少反馈
get there's a there's a few wrinkles
到那里有一些皱纹
that we have still found that we're
我们仍然发现我们
working away but we expect the GA well
努力工作，但我们希望GA表现良好
at the latest at the end of the year but
最迟在今年年底
we expect to be able to do it in the
我们希望能够在
beginning of December very cool um what
12月初很酷，嗯
is the purpose of the ID stored in the
ID的目的是存储在
complaint class any idea all right so
投诉课任何想法都可以
when when you apply an event axel needs
当您应用事件时，轴需要
to another which aggregate apply that
应用于另一个合计
event and so the the ID field is used is
事件，因此使用了ID字段是
actually for axon to to be able to
实际上使轴突能够
identify the the aggregate that
确定汇总
published events so when you load an
已发布的事件，因此当您加载
aggregate it knows exactly which which
汇总它确切知道哪个
events to load from the from the event
从事件中加载事件
store but a correlation would
存储，但相关
yeah exactly well and when you when you
是的，当你当你
load an aggregate from the event store
从事件存储中加载聚合
you don't want to load all the events in
您不想加载所有事件
the beginning of time and you'll see
时间的开始，你会看到
which one's apply but you want to be
哪个适用，但您想成为
able to really specifically find those
能够真正地找到那些
events that have been generated by that
该事件所产生的事件
specific aggregate in the past and only
过去且仅特定的总计
replay them so yeah they correlate the
重播它们，是的，它们与
aggregate instance to the events very
将实例聚合到事件中
cool um let's see how how do you support
酷，让我们看看你如何支持
how do you support a reporting with
您如何支持以下方面的报告
distributed micro-services reporting in
分布式微服务报告
what dens that's the question
这是什么问题
how about reporting with distributing
分发报告如何
micro sources I would thought that would
微型资源，我认为那会
have been kind of the I mean the read
有点像我的意思是读
model kind of gives you what you need
模型可以满足您的需求
there doesn't it the idea of having
没有这个想法
multiple read models you could do as
您可以作为多个读取模型
advanced Oh bill the video is it
高级哦，视频是吗
monitoring or yeah well I mean um so if
监控还是很好，我是说嗯，如果
you are probably so if you have a read
如果您有阅读的话，可能是这样
model that consists of a lot of
包含很多
different is quite likely and please
不同的可能性很大，请
correct me if I'm wrong but quite often
如果我错了就纠正我，但是经常
in reporting you combine information
在报告中您结合了信息
from a lot of different sources and so
来自许多不同的来源等等
yep in it effectively what you have is
有效地拥有它是
just a new view model that has many
只是一个具有许多新视图模型
sources of of its events so it might be
其事件的来源，因此可能是
it depends a bit on how you like your
这取决于您的喜好
deployment model if you have a events or
部署模型（如果您有事件或
per service you probably need to read
您可能需要阅读的每种服务
from multiple event stores and then
从多个事件存储，然后
somehow order those those events a bit
以某种方式命令那些事件
but yeah basically you just have a
但是是的，基本上你只有一个
different view model and you pick your
不同的视图模型，然后选择
events from any source that you want to
您想要来自任何来源的事件
combine them and then build your view
合并它们，然后建立您的视图
model and and that's the part I like I
模型，这就是我喜欢的部分
mean it's not that really that different
意味着不是真的那么不同
from from anything else it's just events
从其他任何事件
as a source and you build whatever you
作为资源，您可以构建自己的任何东西
think is useful to to provide your
认为有助于提供您的
end-users
终端用户
very good let's see
很好，让我们看看
oh yeah the question is the question has
哦，是的，问题是
been refined
被提炼
what about reporting across databases
跨数据库报告怎么办
how do you do sequel joins but I guess
你如何续集加入，但我猜
that I think that is I think the answer
我认为那是我认为答案
I think that's it yeah
我想就是这样
exactly so you don't really well there's
完全是这样，所以您不太舒服
two ways to it right you could either
两种正确的选择
use a combined stream so you use stream
使用组合流，所以您使用流
events from multiple sources and then
来自多个来源的事件，然后
create a nice reporting model or do it I
创建一个不错的报告模型或执行
guess the way that some micro-services
猜测一些微服务的方式
at least do it is you query one and then
至少是您查询一个，然后
query the other one enjoying the data
查询另一个喜欢数据的人
that way I'm not sure if that's really
这样我不确定那是否真的
efficient but everything depends and so
高效但是一切都取决于
it depends on how does it need to be
这取决于它需要如何
fast is it a frequent query you say
您说的查询是否频繁
there once in a once in a year style
一年一次的风格
query or though there's different
查询或有什么不同
options there but my first thoughts go
选项在那里，但我首先想到的是
in the direction of combine those
在结合那些方向
streams and build a model out of out of
流，并从中建立模型
data information but if we learned
数据信息，但如果我们了解到
anything from ghostbusters you should
你应该从鬼魂破坏者那里得到任何东西
never cross the streams
永不越过溪流
no that is well it depends I mean it
不，那很好，这取决于我的意思
gives you very powerful things right you
给您非常强大的功能
can sometimes you really need it
有时您真的需要吗
um let's see what else we got here how
嗯，让我们看看我们还能得到什么
do you ensure that our videos have to do
您是否确保我们的视频必须
with zoo by the way never mind yes it's
与动物园顺便说一句是的
awesome how do you how do you ensure
很棒，你如何确保
that the event is saved to the event
该事件已保存到该事件
store and sent via AMQP atomically how
原子存储并通过AMQP发送如何
would this work with for example Kafka
可以与例如Kafka一起使用吗
and a no sequel store yeah so that's a
还有没有续集的商店，所以那是
good question and well where we're
好问题，以及我们在哪里
sending data to two different systems so
发送数据到两个不同的系统
a guarantee is it doesn't exist but we
保证是不存在，但我们
can get pretty far so in this
可以走得很远
case what happens is a transaction is
如果发生交易是
started and since we're using spring
开始，因为我们使用弹簧
it's using Springs transaction a
它正在使用Springs交易
platform transaction manager and the
平台交易经理和
platform transaction manager it can can
可以的平台交易管理器
hook in a lot of different transactions
进行很多不同的交易
so you can combine the database
所以你可以结合数据库
transaction and baam complete
交易和担保完成
transaction in one well in a kind of one
一口井中的一口交易
kind of because the commits happen very
有点是因为提交发生的非常
good shortly after each other what
彼此不久之后好
action does do is it will send the data
动作所做的就是它将发送数据
to the event store and flush any any
到事件存储并刷新任何
data so it will force the data to go to
数据，因此它将迫使数据转到
the events then events are sent to an
然后将事件发送到
okapi and then the commit happens for
okapi，然后提交发生
for both of them so that's how it can I
为他们两个，所以我可以
feed right nappy if you need stronger
如果您需要更强壮的尿布
guarantee there's an alternative you can
保证有替代方案可以
store it to the events or only some fee
将其存储到事件中或仅收取一些费用
and then have an a it's only getting
然后有一个它只会
frequent giveaway but and then you have
频繁的赠品，然后你有
the processor track the event store and
处理器跟踪事件存储并
send everything it finds to aim deep and
将发现的所有内容都发送出去
in that case all you have at least one
在这种情况下，您至少拥有一个
delivery guarantee in that case which it
那种情况下的交付保证
might be better than an ad most ones
可能比大多数广告更好
guarantee but exactly once I mean it's
保证，但就在我的意思是
been said many times there's still a lot
人们说过很多次了
of debate around it but it doesn't exist
关于它的辩论，但它不存在
there's no way for two systems to to
没有两个系统可以
guarantee on that on mutual state
保证相互状态
without quantum entanglement okay oh I'm
没有量子纠缠，好吧，我是
being told I should mute my line that's
有人告诉我应该让我的电话静音
probably the feedback is but in finance
可能是反馈，但在财务方面
talk what does David edit um okay so
说说大卫编辑了什么，好吧
what action be able to support a
什么动作能够支持一个
distribute right model yes was the
分配权利模型是
question will or does because it is yeah
问题是或不是因为是
does accent support a distributor right
口音是否支持分销商权利
model I think there's actually two phase
我认为实际上有两个阶段
commit kind of discussion as opposed to
进行某种讨论而不是
writing two different things but take it
写两个不同的东西，但要接受
any way you want well the way action
任何你想要的方式
does it is more so you have these
还有更多，所以你有这些
aggregates
骨料
an aggregate will always live in one
骨料永远活在一个
location right it lives an aggregate
正确的位置居住
instance will live in one one location
实例将位于一个位置
if it lives in two locations then you
如果它住在两个地方，那么你
get some problems further down the
进一步解决一些问题
stream that they're trying to insert the
他们试图插入的流
same event into the event store which is
相同事件进入事件存储
then rejected but the way you can
然后拒绝，但是你可以的方式
distribute it you can shard your your
分发它，您可以分片您的
aggregates over multiple nodes and axon
聚集在多个节点和轴突上
does happen to the distributed command
确实发生在分布式命令上
bus and if we had an hour and a half of
巴士，如果我们有一个半小时
the webinar then I could have shown that
网络研讨会，那么我可以证明
as well there's actually a starter for
其实还有一个入门
it as well is the axon spring booth
它也是轴突弹簧展位
starter J groups and it allows you to to
入门级J组，它使您能够
start up nodes and then these nose
启动节点，然后这些鼻子
detect each other and they start sharing
互相检测并开始共享
or balancing the the load among each
或平衡每个之间的负载
other based on a consistent hashing
其他基于一致的哈希
algorithm so the every client will know
算法，这样每个客户都会知道
to send a command to a specific nodes
向特定节点发送命令
simply because it targets in an
只是因为它以
aggregate and then based on that
聚合，然后基于
aggregate identifier you can find the
您可以找到汇总标识符
the correct node to where to send it to
将其发送到的正确节点
so that's how you can leave scale the
这样便可以留下刻度
command side and get some distribution
命令端并获得一些分配
over there what you cannot do and should
那边你不能做的事应该
not do by definition I would say just to
按照定义，我不会说
be really annoying is distribute a
真的很烦人是分发
single aggregate over multiple nodes
多个节点上的单个聚合
because the definition of an aggregate
因为聚合的定义
is a it's a group of entities that
是一组实体
together act as one with regard to data
一起作为数据
changes as soon as you start
一开始就改变
distributing that well it's that's not
分配得很好不是
my not my view of simple systems simple
我不是我对简单系统的看法
to maintain systems it's not an area
维护系统不是一个领域
it's not an aggregate anymore exactly if
如果不是，那将不再是一个合计
events need to be processed by consumers
事件需要由消费者处理
in a sequence easy consumer a must
顺便要求消费者必须
process em in X before consumer B how do
在消费者B之前在X中处理em怎么办
you do that with accent um interesting
你会很有趣
that here we go again sorry
那我们又去了对不起
so if if two consumers are part of so
所以如果两个消费者是其中的一部分
remember I was talking about these
记得我在说这些
processing groups and these processors
处理组和这些处理器
is they are part of the same processors
它们是同一处理器的一部分吗
group there are ways to define that the
组中有一些方法可以定义
consumers should be invoked in specific
消费者应在特定条件下调用
order
订购
hi if they are part of different
嗨，如果他们是不同的一部分
applications then there is no guarantee
应用程序就没有保证
[Music]
[音乐]
there's no guarantee at all or any humor
根本没有任何保证或任何幽默
to handle the the event before any other
在其他事件之前处理事件
one does it cool already um oh what else
它已经很酷了吗，哦，还有什么
do we got here I think we're actually at
我们到达这里了吗我认为我们实际上在
a good oh there's another question how
很好哦还有另一个问题
to scale the commands but I'm not really
缩放命令，但我不是真的
sure I understand that I think that has
确定我了解我认为
to do with what I said earlier with
与我之前说的有关
distributors come on bus and then that's
分销商坐公交车，然后
how you can scale them right all right I
我怎样才能正确地缩放它们
didn't have multiple note concurrently
同时没有多个音符
dealing with events as long as there are
只要有事件就可以处理
four different aggregates right all the
四个不同的集合
commands for a single aggregate are
单个聚合的命令是
always invoked sequentially and that
总是顺序地调用，
makes the programming model of
使得编程模型
aggregates nicer but it also makes an
聚合更好，但也使
aggregate and aggregate is by definition
聚集和聚集是根据定义
you cannot concurrently execute stuff on
您不能同时执行
an aggregate good point good good
总的来说好点好点
insight um by the way going back to that
嗯，回溯到那个
question about reporting for microscope
有关显微镜报告的问题
or ting across different micro services
或跨不同的微服务
um there's a good my friend Ben Wilcock
嗯，有个好朋友我的朋友本·威尔考克
is a just pointed me to a very good
只是指出我非常好
resource the Microsoft developer Network
Microsoft开发人员网络的资源
they have a book called an ebook ebook
他们有一本书叫电子书电子书
called the CQRS journey and I guess they
叫做CQRS旅程，我想他们
speak to that a little bit in there as
跟那边说一点
well so check that out it's free is
好吧，请检查一下它是免费的
available looks interesting um okay so
可用看起来很有趣，嗯，所以
last question how does exon fit with
最后一个问题外显子如何与
with vertex which is a
顶点是
which is more of an event that's right
这更像是对的事件
it doesn't actually solve the problem to
它实际上并不能解决问题
secure it it's just an event I didn't
确保它只是我没有的一个事件
know I'm still finding ways to some some
知道我还在寻找一些方法
people I I know are very into vertex and
我知道的人非常喜欢顶点
they they've been trying to see if how
他们一直在尝试看看是否
does it fit with axon and and I think
它适合轴突吗？我认为
axon is a bit larger than vertex just in
轴突比顶点略大
in the scope of the architectural
在建筑范围内
pattern that it tries to address vertex
尝试解决顶点的模式
is more of an event event handling
更多的是事件事件处理
mechanism right everything I mean
我的意思是正确的机制
there's a lot of concepts that are
有很多概念
similar so vertex has this event loop
类似，因此顶点具有此事件循环
and then every action is its own little
然后每个动作都是自己的
thread or a process I don't think they
线程或进程，我不认为他们
really use threading but they use some
确实使用线程，但他们使用一些
other mechanism back and then everything
其他机制，然后一切
is a is the only vent loop right so yeah
是唯一的排气回路吗，是的
you can build stuff with vertex I have
你可以用我拥有的顶点来构建东西
never seen a very nice combination of
从来没有见过一个很好的组合
the two that I thought you know it does
我以为你知道的那两个
work for samples but I would never build
为样品工作，但我永远不会建立
an application as far as I've seen right
据我所见正确的应用程序
now based on both technology so if one
现在基于两种技术，所以如果一个
fits and probably the other doesn't and
适合，另一个可能不适合
vice versa
反之亦然
cool very good all right um I think
很好，很好，嗯，我想
that's it my friend I think we did is
就是我的朋友，我想我们做的是
have we got through all those questions
我们是否解决了所有这些问题
and this time it only took 25 minutes
这次只用了25分钟
instead of the 27 or so minutes it took
而不是花了27分钟左右
last time so I think we just I think we
上次，所以我认为我们只是我认为我们
did pretty good all right well I hope
很好，很好，我希望
everybody said I answered all the
大家都说我回答了
questions to the satisfaction of whoever
令任何人满意的问题
asked them right on and or so don't I
马上问他们，所以我不
was actually just get in touch with us
实际上只是与我们联系
right right we're on the internet you
对吧，我们在互联网上
got our Twitter information and that
得到了我们的Twitter信息，那
slide there for those of you still in
滑到那里，让那些仍在的人
line thank you so much for joining us
行非常感谢您加入我们
this video has been recorded it'll be
该视频已被记录下来
available online on spring that IO for
可以在春季在线上获得IO
such video within a week or so I'd
这样的视频，我会在一周左右的时间内
imagine it's it's not it
想象是不是
- sure but probably it might you know
-当然可以，但也许你知道
might be sooner than that who knows and
可能比谁知道的要早
we look forward to seeing you again in
我们期待再次与您见面
our next webinar our next installment so
下一次网络研讨会我们的下一部分
thank you very much and have a good day
非常感谢你，祝你有美好的一天
all right but
可以，但是
you
您